https://www.defender.com/privacy.jsp

Defender Industries Privacy Statement
The website www.defender.com is owned and operated by Defender Industries, Inc.
You may contact us by any of the following methods:
Call us at 860-701-3400 or 800-628-8225
Email us at privacy@defender.com
Write us at:
Privacy Compliance
Defender Industries, Inc.
42 Great Neck Road
Waterford, CT 06385-3336 USA
Our Data Controller is: Brent Tuttle and he may be reached at the address and phone numbers above.Please allow 30 days for a written response.
Right to Privacy and Compliance with EU GDPR
We know your data privacy is important to you, and we believe in transparency when it comes to our customers' privacy rights.
We take stringent precautions to protect your personal information and we never share your personal information with other parties.
In compliance with the new EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), you have the right to restrict the way Defender uses personal data.
You may request that your data be removed for any or all contact lists as well as request that your personal data be erased completely from Defender's records.
You may also request a record of your personal information that Defender is currently storing.
More specific information about how your data is used is presented below.
California Consumer Privacy Act (CCPA)
Effective January 1, 2020:
Defender Industries does not share or sell any of your information.
You have the right to request that your personal information is removed from Defender Industries' systems.
If you wish to have all of your information removed from our systems, please contact us by any of the following methods:
Call us at 1- 800-628-8225
Email us at privacy@defender.com
Write us at:
Privacy Compliance
Defender Industries
42 Great Neck Road
Waterford, CT 06385-3336 USA
Please allow 30 days for a written response.
If you have any questions about our Privacy Policy, please email us at: privacy@defender.com
Or visit the State of California website regarding the California Consumer Privacy Act (CCPA) at the following link:https://oag.ca.gov/privacy/ccpa
Anonymous Access
You can access our Web site's home page and browse our sites without disclosing your personal data.
Automatic Collection of Information
When you visit our websites, our web servers automatically recognize only the IP address (where possible), but not your e-mail address.
We collect only the domain name (but not your e-mail address) of visitors to our websites and aggregate information on what pages visitors access or visit.
The information we collect is used for internal review to improve the content and functionality of our websites, is then discarded, and is not shared with any other organizations.
Email Address Collection and Usage
We collect the e-mail addresses of those who communicate with us via e-mail, and information volunteered by the consumer, such as survey information and/or site registrations, but neither the e-mail address nor the information volunteered is shared with other organizations.
We will contact you via e-mail only as required to verify information that you have provided or requested.
We collect and maintain an opt-in e-mail address list of consumers who wish to receive notices from us regarding new products, special events and offers.
We never share your email with others.
You must opt-in to our mailing list to begin receiving our regular e-mail notices of special offerings.
We clearly provide you with an option to opt-out within every scheduled email we send to you.
If you do not want to receive notices via e-mail from us in the future, please let us know at https://www.defender.com/email_list.jsp, or by sending us e-mail at the address above, calling us at the telephone number above, or writing to us at the address above.
Cookies
We use cookies to store visitor preferences, record session information, such as items that consumers add to their shopping cart, and to record user-specific information on what pages users access or visit.
Cookies provide a convenience feature to save you time, or tell the web servers that you have returned to a specific page.
For example, if you personalize pages on our websites, or register for the Subscription Service, a cookie helps recall your specific information on subsequent visits.
When you return to the same website, the information you previously provided can be retrieved, so you can easily use the customized features.
Cookies set by our website are called "first-party cookies".
Cookies set by parties other than our website are called "third-party cookies".
Third-party cookies enable third-party features or functionality to be provided on or through the website, like analytics.
Defender does not participate with any advertising networks, and does not use clear gifs, web beacons, web bugs or flash cookies.
You can access and browse our website without enabling cookies, but you will not be able to keep items in your shopping cart.
The functionality of the website will be limited without cookies enabled.
Data Collection and Purpose
We collect the personal data that you may volunteer while using our services, which may include, but is not limited to:
Name
Postal Mailing Address
Shipping Address
Telephone Number and/or Fax Number
e-mail address
If you supply us with your postal address on-line, you will only receive the information for which you provided us your address.
Persons who supply us with their telephone numbers on-line will only receive telephone contact from us with information regarding orders they have placed on-line.
Upon request we provide site visitors with access to unique identifier information (e.g., customer number or password) that we maintain about them, transaction information (e.g., dates on which customers made purchases, amounts and types of purchases) that we maintain about them, contact information (e.g., name, address, phone number) that we maintain about them.
Consumers can access or have this information corrected by sending us e-mail at the address above, calling us at the telephone number above, or writing to us at the address above.
Confidentiality / Security
We provide a secure transmission method to send us the following types of personal data:
Identifiers (such as credit card details, etc.). Note: Your credit card information is never stored on our web sites, so you must re-enter it each time you place on on-line order.
We have implemented security policies, rules and technical measures to protect the personal data that we have under our control from:
Unauthorized access
Improper use or disclosure
Unauthorized modification
Unlawful destruction or accidental loss
All our employees and data processors, who have access to, and are associated with the processing of personal data, are obliged to respect the confidentiality of our visitors' personal data.
We use industry-standard encryption technologies when transferring and receiving consumer data exchanged with our site.
With respect to Ad Servers: We do not partner with or have special relationships with any ad server companies.
Telephone Conversations
Defender retains telephone conversation history so we can more easily recall previous conversations and pick up where we left off from previous calls.
A request to erase personal information will erase telephone records.
Children's Privacy
We do not knowingly collect personal data from children.
We do, however, sell products intended for children that may be purchased by adults.
Disclosure and Visitor Choice
We do not disclose your personal data to other organizations.
We ensure that your personal data will not be disclosed to State institutions and authorities except if required by law or other regulation.
From time to time, we may use customer information for new, unanticipated uses not previously disclosed in our privacy notice.
If our information practices change at some time in the future, we will post the policy changes to our website to notify you of these changes and provide you with the ability to opt out of these new uses.
If you are concerned about how your information is used, you should check back at our website periodically.
If we wish to use your personal data for new purposes, we offer you the means to consent to those new purposes by calling us at the number provided above, e-mailing us at the address above, or writing us at the address above.
Customers may prevent their information from being used for purposes other than those for which it was originally collected by calling us at the number provided above, e-mailing us at the address above, or writing us at the address above.
Accountability
Defender Industries, Inc. is not responsible for, and cannot be held liable for, the content or services at web sites that we provide links to.
Visits to other web sites via our provided links require you to leave our web sites, and we have no control over their Privacy Policies.
Please review the Privacy Policy of each web site that you visit if you are concerned about your privacy.
Your privacy is a serious concern of ours, so if you feel that this site is not following its stated information policy, please contact us immediately at the above address or phone number.
If you have an unresolved dispute with us over our Privacy Policy, please feel free to contact the DMA's Committee on Ethical Business Practices at mgoldberger@the-dma.org, state or local chapters of the Better Business Bureau, state or local consumer protection office, The Federal Trade Commission by phone at 202.FTC-HELP (202.382.4357) or electronically at http://www.ftc.gov/ftc/complaint.htm.
Defender Industries, Inc. reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time.
Privacy Policy last updated and effective date: January 1, 2020
